[MUSIC]
[背景音乐] 翻译: RyukaSuu |审阅: 19waa Coursera Global Translator Community
So now we understand information visualization.
现在我们已经理解了信息可视化
We can start to think of how we would design an information
我们可以开始思考该如何设计一个信息
visualization system.
可视化系统
So when creating a visualization system, you're really creating a user interface.
当创建一个可视化系统时 你其实就是在创造用户界面
It's an interface between the user and the data facilitated by a computer.
这是用户和电脑促进生成的数据之间的界面
And so data visualization systems are really graphical user interfaces.
所以数据可视化系统其实就是用户界面
You're using the computer to graphically represent the data.
你使用电脑来用图表表示数据
So principles from user interface design are important in constructing a good,
因此用户界面的设计原理对建设一个好的
effective visualization system.
有效的可视化系统是很重要的
You already have an understanding of the system,
现在你已经对这个系统有所了解
of how the graphics works in the system, and how we display data with the system.
如图像在系统中的运作以及我们如何在系统中显示数据
You have a good understanding of how users work
在课程的第一模块中
based on what we covered in Module 1 of this course.
你也了解到了用户是如何与系统交互的
We'll also need to focus on the goals.
我们也需要来专注下目标
What does the user hope to achieve, and
用户想要达到的目标是什么
the tasks that they'll be performing to achieve those goals.
以及他们为了达到目的所要完成的任务
And also the interaction.
当然还有交互
We'll need to be able to represent and understand the interaction of the user and
我们需要能够表示和理解用户与系统的交互
the system, and, for example, describe a dialogue,
比如 描述一段对话
a language of clicks and selections, and so on, so
或是一段让用户点击和选择的一段话等
that the users can perform tasks in a way that's intuitive and productive.
以便能让用户用直觉的 有成效的方式完成任务
So we'll follow some standard sequences of forming a system design.
我们会按照标准的顺序来完成一个系统设计
Designing a visualization system is similar to designing a software system or
设计一个可视化系统和设计软件系统或
other systems in general.
其他一般的系统很类似
We start with a basic requirement specification.
我们从基本的需求说明开始
And that's basically going to try to figure out what specific
其实就是尝试弄明白这个系统
problems the system is going to solve.
要解决哪些问题
Who's the system going to serve?
系统会为谁服务
And how will that person be able to make a decision
那个人怎么样才能根据你设计的可视化系统
based on your visualization system?
做出决策
This involves a lot of discussions with the user.
这需要你和用户大量沟通
I see focus groups used for this, but it's important that the focus groups and
我看到过有利用专题小组座谈或用户采访的
interviews with the user aren't asking the user specifically what kind of
但用户采访时重要的是不要询问用户
interface or what kind of visualization system they want,
他们想要哪种界面或可视化系统
because you're going to be the expert of the visualization system.
因为你将是设计该可视化系统的专家
Often the users don't know what's out there, what's available,
通常用户不会知道现在的情况和有什么可选
what will serve them best, and so you want to focus on what questions they want to
最适合他们的是什么 所以你应该问一些他们想回答的
answer with the system and how can you get that information to them so
关于系统的问题 并且如何更好地传递给他们信息
that they'll have everything they need to answer those questions.
以使他们有足够的信息来回答那些问题
Then there's an architectural design, and
然后是构架设计
this is breaking the full system down into component systems.
这相当于把完整的系统分解成不同的分系统
If you're making a visualization dashboard,
如果你在做一个可视化仪表盘
then these would be the individual elements of that dashboard.
那么这里的分系统指的就是仪表盘上的单个组件
And then there's a component design that
就是分系统的设计了
you're going to figure out how to implement each of those elements.
你需要弄清楚如何实现单个的组件
And then you go through a step of actually implementing, actually coding or
然后就是具体实施 通过具体的编码或
setting up the system for each of these components.
或建立系统来真正地实现这些组件
Then you do some debugging to test each of the components.
然后你调试这些组件
And then an important step is user evaluation.
接下来很重要的一步是用户评估
Once you have these components, you'll want to make sure and
这些组件齐备之后 你需要确保与用户一起
test them with users to make sure they're doing want they're supposed to be doing,
测试这些组件 并确保所有各组件按要求正常运行
that the user is using them the way that you intended to use them.
用户也是按你预计的方式来使用它们
And also to use some statistics to make sure that you're not just basing your
当然你也要用一些统计数据来确保 你的评估
evaluation on anecdotal evidence, but
不是建立在猜测上
that the user is actually using the system effectively.
而是用户确实在有效的使用这个系统
And then finally maintenance documentations for the system and fixing.
最后市系统维护的文档和维修
It's easy to underestimate this process, and when people make estimates of how
理解这个过程很容易 但当人们估算
long it will take to implement such systems they, focus on implementation, and
需要多久来实现这个系统时 往往只注重实施阶段的时间
you'll see implementation is maybe one of seven steps here.
而你会看到实施也许只是七个步骤之一
And that's why we say when we're designing software systems or user interfaces or
这也是为什么我们说 在我们设计软件系统 或用户交互界面 或者
visualization systems, you want to take the amount of time you think it should
可视化系统的时候 你需要在你认为需要的总的时间上
take, and then you want to double it.
再加倍
And by doubling it, you're then realizing that you're going to have to be
这加倍的时间 你将意识到你终会用在
doing debugging and some component design.
做一些调试或者组件的设计上
And then you want to double it again, because you also need to do the analysis
然后你还需要把时间翻倍 因为你也需要时间做一些分析
and the requirements specification and the evaluation and the maintenance.
以及需求说明 系统评估和维护等
And so, if we tend to underestimate by just looking at implementation,
所以 如果只考虑实施阶段 我们通常会低估时间
it really takes six to eight times as long to actually create a system
实际需要耗费六至八倍的时间 来真正组建一个系统
when you're doing it right.
以确保系统正确
Some other advice when making these systems is to use prototypes.
关于创造这个系统的一些其他的建议 是使用概念设计或雏形设计
We talk about user evaluation here at the end, but you should be doing user
我们在最后谈到用户的评估 但是你应该
evaluations and user testings at every stage of this, checking with the user
在制作系统的每一个阶段上进行用户评估和测试
in some form or another, either with a model of the user or with the actual user.
利用模拟用户或是真正的用户
And so you want to use prototypes to simulate how the system might work when
所以在制定用户说明时 你需要利用雏型 来模拟实际系统将是如何工作的
you're doing a requirement specification and then move to an architectural design.
之后进行构架设计
For the architectural design, you might want to have a mockup of
对于构架设计 你也许需要有制作一些草图
a possible interface and put that in front of the user to determine that that
来表示可能的用户界面 并呈现给用户
meets the requirements that the system needs to provide.
以确认系统符合用户需求
Or, you may even have a Wizard of Oz system where you simulate the system
或者 在一些特例中 你可能甚至用一个绿野仙踪般神奇的系统
without it actually working the way it's supposed to on a very specific case.
来模拟系统 而不需要照实际系统那样运行
You can hard-code a system to work and
你可以通过预设值使系统工作
you can see as you're doing component design if that was in a biosystem,
如在一生物系统进行组件设计中会遇到
that simulation of the system that you designed is going to satisfy it
在实际实施系统之前 通过仿真来验证
before you actually invest the time in implementing the system.
设计将符合要求
You don't always have to go back to the user to get these answers.
你不需要总是回到用户那里来获得答案
Often, especially as you're working on the design stages of the system,
通常 特别是在系统设计阶段
that you can use models of the task and dialog.
你能使用任务以及对话框的模型
So the user model, based on the requirement specification you'll have
所以这个基于需求说明的用户模型
an idea of what goals the user will want to solve.
能帮助你了解用户实际需要实现的目标
And you can start decomposing tasks and
你可开始分解任务
creating task analyses that go into the layout of components
并且开始进行组件布局的分析任务
that can make sure that they meet the requirements as specified.
以确定它们符合指定的需求
And finally, as I mentioned before,
最后 就像我之前提到过的
don't wait until the very end to do this component testing.
不要等待到最后 才进行组件测试
You'll want to test each of these if you've created a good model of the user,
在你建好用户模型 对话框 和任务之后
and the dialog, and the tasks, and so on.
你需要对其中每一项进行测试
You can start to do some testing of your design before you've invested in
你可以在启动实施工作之前即
the implementation time.
开始测试你的设计
So for user modeling, there's a variety of different techniques for modeling users.
所以对于用户模型 有许多不同的技术来实现
You want to focus on what the user needs to answer a question.
你要专注于用户需要什么去回答一个问题
You want to provide a visualization that will help the user answer a question, and
你需要提供可视化来帮助用户回答问题
you don't necessarily want to create the fanciest visualization or
你并不一定要制作最漂亮的可视化界面
use every facility that's available on the computer system.
或者使用在电脑系统上所有的功能
You want to try to get into the head of the user.
你需要知道用户在想什么
Try to look at the system from the user's point of view instead of, for example,
尝试从用户的角度来看系统 而不是 比如说
the programmer's point of view, or a system designer's point of view.
从程序员的角度来看 或者系统设计者的角度
And you want to know your user.
你想要了解你的用户
What's the user familiar with?
用户熟悉什么?
What other tools are they using?
他们在用其他什么工具?
What's the user's role among other users, or
用户在其他用户中扮演什么角色
among other people in their organization?
或是在他们的机构中扮演什么角色?
What might the user know, and what might the user not understand?
用户可能知道什么以及用户可能不理解什么?
And then finally, what's the users motivation in using the system?
最后 用户使用这个系统的动机是什么?
How can you best provide the information in a way that the user
你能最好以什么方式提供给用户信息
will want to use the system and know what to do to properly use the system?
来方便用户使用系统并且知道如何合理的使用
Finally, it's good to do a cognitive walkthrough,
最后 进行认知调查是有益的
put yourself in the head of the user and map out, write out in diagrams
把你自己放在用户的角度来制定出详细的图表
what should be on the mind of the user as they're using your visualization system,
想象一下 当用户使用你的可视化系统的时候 他们脑海中在想什么
so that you can better present data based on what the user is currently focusing on.
这样你就能够基于用户目前的关注的 更好展现数据
And so there's a variety of user modelling techniques, one of them is an old one,
用户建模的方法有很多 其中一个使用很久的方法
it's called GOMS.
叫做GOMS
It stands for goals, operators, methods, and selections,
GOMS 四个字母分别代表目标 操作者 方法和选择
and it helps you to understand what a user might be thinking of.
这能够帮助你了解一个用户的可能想法
Users are going to be goal-oriented, and so it's good to map out the goals for
用户是目标导向的 所以为整个系统规划蓝图
the system.
系统中建造了幻觉。
It's also good to think of the operators as you're designing the system.
在你设计这个系统的时候 想想操作者会怎么做也是十分有益的
What are the operations,
有些什么操作
the basic user actions that the user's going to be using to achieve the goals?
即用户需要哪些基本的操作来实现目标?
And the user's going to be forming methods by stringing together these operations,
用户将结合这些操作来形成方法
and there may be multiple methods of achieving a goal.
也许有多种方法来实现目标
Which ones are you going to support, try to support as many of them,
你将支持哪一个方法 去尝试支持更多
there's more than one way to skin a cat.
给猫剥皮往往有很多方法
Users will have different methods to achieve a goal, and
使用者将会有不同的方法来实现一个目标
you want to be as flexible as possible in supporting those.
这种支持越灵活越好
And then finally, selections.
最后一步 选择
When there's multiple methods, the user's going to have different ways of selecting
如果有多重方法 那么 用户就有多重方式选择使用哪一种方法
which method to use, and you want to provide as much information as possible to
这时你要提供尽量详尽的信息
be able to make an appropriate selection.
以帮助用户做出最合适的选择
A user's going to have a goal, and each goal is going to have a task or
用户有一个目标 且每个目标都有一个或者
multiple tasks associated with achieving that goal, and so
多个相关任务
you want to make sure that your system can connect tasks into goals,
所以你要确保你的系统能够将任务变成目标
and so this is the principal of user interface design called synthesizability.
这就是用户界面设计的原则 叫做"可综合性"
Is a user sitting in front of your system going to know how to use your system
如果你有一个可视化面板的话
to arrive at an answer if you have a visualization dashboard?
用户在这个面板前是否知道如何使用这个系统 来获得答案?
Is the user going to know where to look at on your dashboard in order to be
用户是否可以通过面板提供的信息
able to come to a conclusion based on the information presented?
而得出有关结论?
And so these tasks often get complicated, and so
这些任务还会变的复杂
you'll need to decompose tasks into subtasks and goals into subgoals,
所以你需要简化 将任务变成子任务 目标变成子目标
and then tasks will follow a sequence, and those sequences are plans.
之后任务将会有一定的顺序 这个顺序就是计划
And how can you articulate that plan so that the user can synthesize it when
那么 你将如何清楚的表达这个计划
they're sitting in front of you visualization system?
以便使用户通过你的可视化系统 可以进行综合?
You may want to look at conditional tasks when a selection needs to be made.
如果需要进行选择的话 你也许需要考虑条件性任务
What are the triggers for a conditional task?
条件性任务的触发点是什么？
When does a subwindow need to be opened?
什么时候需要开子窗口?
When can some operations be avoided?
什么时候一些操作可以省去?
You might also consider wait times, delays in information processing, or
你可能还得考虑等待时间 信息处理的延迟
when the user is interrupted, cyclic tasks or multiple parallel tasks.
或者什么时候用户被打断 或者循环任务 并行任务等
And then you can use all of these results to sort of imply the best
之后你可根据这些结果来实现最好的界面
dashboard layout that best facilitates the user getting the information they need
以帮助用户获得他们需要的信息
to be able to make a good informed decision.
来做出一个明智的决定
So here's some examples of dashboards.
这里有一些面板的例子
This is a old dashboard from 2001 SIGCHI visualization,
这是一个旧的可视面板图 出自2001的 SIGCHI （人机交互特别兴趣群体）
but it would still be used in modern contexts.
但是它在现在依旧能被使用
It's used if you're monitoring newsgroups or online conversations.
它可用于监管在线会话和新闻组讨论
We've had these for 15 years and longer.
我们有这种面板15年甚至更长的时间了
And this one's shown to work really well.
依旧使用良好
It starts with a thread tree, and it's basically a conversation with a subject,
最初它是一种基于主体对话的线程树
and then people replying to that subject.
即用户对主体进行回应
And other people are replying to the original subject, and
有人先对原始的主体回应
people are replying to the second reply to the original subject.
然后其他的人则对初始的回应再回应
And so you get this tree like behavior.
所以你得到类似如树的表现
And it's organized chronologically, vertically but
这种组织是按时间顺序的 纵向的
then you form a hierarchy based on replying.
也就形成了基于回应的层次结构
Which messages reply to which other messages?
哪些信息回应了其它哪些信息呢?
And then you've got the users, and the users are provided here in this
这里还有用户信息 用户的信息表示在这第二个可视化图中
second visualization, and you have kind of a Gantt chart called a piano roll.
你就有了类似如甘特图的图形 也被叫做钢琴卷
And it's basically corresponding to posting which messages in
这基本对应于横向是随时间而发布的信息
time horizontally, and then you've got it sorted vertically by the number of posts.
而纵向则是依发布的信息条数来排序
And then you've got this sociogram,in this case it's just a social network,
然后你就能获得这个社会关系网图 在这个情况下就是个社交网络
just a graph where you've got connections based on who's replying to whose message.
只是一个基于谁对谁的信息有回应的图表
But the horizontal and vertical position of nodes
至于节点的水平位置和垂直位置
is indicating horizontally the number of responses each person sends, and
在水平方向上的数字表示每一个人发出的回应
vertically by the number of responses they get.
垂直方向上的数字则表示收到回应
And so this original poster is getting a lot of responses,
所以这种原始的张贴能收到很多的回应
and the rest of these are getting some responses to their posts.
而其余的也有一些回应
And then finally we want details on demand.
最后我们想要根据需要来获取细节
You've got this detail selection so you can select a node here.
你可以选择细节 你可以在这选择一个节点
You can select a person here, it gets highlighted in the thread tree here.
你可在这选择某个人 在这线索树中就被高亮显示
You can select an individual node here and
你可以在这里选择单独的节点
see what the actual post is in order to drill down to those details.
并且会看到实际的张贴以便获取这些细节
Another example of a dashboard is the CDC, Center for
另外一个界面的例子是CDC
Disease Control, FluView which shows in the US how the flu
疾病控制中心 FluView 展示的是流感每年在美国的传播
is progressing through the year and which strains of the flu are occurring.
以及是哪类流感在流行
And so you can see peak times for flu, which strains of the flu are happening,
所以你能看到流感发生的高峰期 和是哪类流感
you get a map here so you can determine by region.
这里有一张图 你按地域来看数据
For example, this is the region where the University of Illinois is, and
比如说 这里是伊利诺伊大学所在的地方
I can see which flus I should be on the lookout for and
我能看到我得注意哪种的流感
which times I should be on the lookout for.
以及什么时候得注意
And I can start to make a decision based on this data how at risk I am or
然后我可以基于这些数据来确定
other people I know might be at risk for the flu.
我本人或其他人可能获得流感的可能性
Andt here's also a Uuniversity of Illinois at Urbana-Chmpaign strategic plan
这里也是伊利诺伊大学厄香槟校区大学的
dashboard.
一个策略计划版图
And we have a strategic plan that has several elements.
我们有一个策略计划其包几个部分
For example, fostering scholarship, discovering innovation, providing
比如说 扶植奖学金 发现创新
transformative learning experiences, societal impact, stewarding resources.
提供变革性的学习经验 社会影响 管理资源
And then we have individual graphs in our dashboard that we can select for
之后我们在界面上 可以选择独立的图表
each of these elements that tell us how we're doing with each of these elements.
这些图表可告诉我们每一部分的情况
But the graphs also don't just give the raw data, they give, for
但是图表并不仅仅提供原始数据
example, goals, where we want to be with some of these elements.
比方说 他们还提供 我们在某些部分的目标
In some cases we're doing well compared to our goals,
在某些情况下 我们所作的比预期目标好
in some cases we're not doing as well compared to our goals.
在其他一些情况下 我们则没有达到目标
And then that can motivate us to do a better job.
所以图表能激励我们将工作做得更好
So following these design rules, these sequences for designing a visualization
所以遵循这些设计的规则 这些设计可视化系统的顺序
system, you can start to design your own dashboard that focuses these
你能开始设计你自己的 基于你自己的数据的
visualization tools on your own data so you can use it to make better decisions.
可视化界面 以便你能使用它更好的做出决策
[MUSIC]
[背景音乐] 翻译: RyukaSuu |审阅: 19waa Coursera Global Translator Community